<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Scream</title>
    <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daily Scream</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:10:18 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.jmarhic.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Podpocket release</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-12-11-podpocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:10:18 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-12-11-podpocket/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated with YouTube Music as a podcast player ever since Google retired &lt;a href=&#34;https://killedbygoogle.com/&#34;&gt;Google Podcast&lt;/a&gt; last year, mostly because they now play ads before each episode! So I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to develop and release a minimal podcast player, &lt;a href=&#34;https://podpocket.jmarhic.com/&#34;&gt;Podpocket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was really a pleasure to develop it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://pocketbase.io/&#34;&gt;Pocketbase&lt;/a&gt;, as it handled everything I need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;authentication (including oauth) setup in a few clicks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a UI to create new collections (sqlite tables), and a complete admin dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even Cron jobs (to refresh the RSS feeds periodically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s written in Go so you can extend it super easily. For instance, I added an endpoint to register new RSS feeds, and I still have a single unified backend. This is unlike Firebase where you end up with a split architecture where some calls go directly to Firebase services and others to your custom backend. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to reuse it in my next project. A fun feature is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pocketbase.io/docs/authentication/#users-impersonation&#34;&gt;user impersonation&lt;/a&gt; that lets an admin login as another user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 11 24 Monday morning</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-11-24-monday-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:03:02 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-11-24-monday-morning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vietnam has been hit hard by heavy rain lately, but the skies were clear this morning. I drove my daughter to school on a scooter, and since we were early we took a longer route across the river. From the bridge we saw a giant rubber duck they installed on the other side of the river, pretty cool ! Arrived at school she asked me to stay for the morning dance, so I watched her jumping to the sound of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V6fGupFWQ7o&#34;&gt;DJ Raphi&amp;rsquo;s ABC song&lt;/a&gt; with 50 other kindergartners. That was an energetic morning ! Just what I needed so I could resume work on this sprint ticket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 11 05 November Update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-11-05-november-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:16:40 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-11-05-november-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot going on these days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I succumbed to the hype and installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://omarchy.org/&#34;&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt;, the new Linux distro by DHH. It&amp;rsquo;s basically Arch Linux with a tiling window manager (&lt;a href=&#34;https://hypr.land/&#34;&gt;Hyprland&lt;/a&gt;), but it comes pre-configured and installable with an ISO, which is super convenient compared to the usual Arch install process. So out of the box you get a very good-looking desktop with nice shortcuts and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some will disagree with DHH&amp;rsquo;s preferences and choices, but realistically I would never have taken the time to configure Hyprland properly myself, so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to rely on somebody&amp;rsquo;s taste (I trust DHH&amp;rsquo;s taste more than mine in that regard!). Same goes for the rest of the desktop environment (waybar for the top bar, walker for the app launcher&amp;hellip;). That was my main issue with Arch, too much choice and alternatives that I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about (I just want internet, not to have to choose a network manager&amp;hellip;). So I really see the appeal of Omarchy for many people, and it seems to be gaining popularity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rip Daniel Narodistky</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-10-24-rip-daniel-narodistky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:01:21 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-10-24-rip-daniel-narodistky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this week saw the passing of Chess Grandmaster and streamer &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DanielNaroditskyGM&#34;&gt;Daniel Narodistky&lt;/a&gt; and it came as a shock for a lot of people including me. I was particularly a fan of his &amp;ldquo;speedrun&amp;rdquo; videos, it really helped demystify chess. I used to think high level chess was this impenetrable mix of &amp;ldquo;opening&amp;rdquo; knowledge and thinking 20 moves in advance, but he really showed how each move made sense in an almost obvious way, either positionally or tactically. Watching his videos you get the feeling that you grasp chess and that, of course you could have won that game too, that was easy ! (only to lose against a 1000 ELO in your next game).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logic riddle (October update)</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-10-15-october-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:04:24 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-10-15-october-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A programmer says &amp;ldquo;I have 2 kids, and the sum of their age is 4&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logician thinks and says &amp;ldquo;not enough info&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programmer adds &amp;ldquo;The eldest likes Bluey&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logician smiles and replies &amp;ldquo;Ah ! You must be using vibe coding a lot&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goverture/goxy&#34;&gt;Goxy&lt;/a&gt;: an OpenAI proxy that track &amp;amp; limit spending. You can set an hourly limit (say 1$ per hour) and the proxy will return 429 errors when the spend reaches the limit. That lets you release LLM using projects while being confident you won&amp;rsquo;t get hit with a thousand-dollar bill at the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>September Update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-09-25-september-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:28:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-09-25-september-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just came back from a two weeks vacation in France with my daughter, and without my laptop, which was pretty nice. As a result I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say for this month !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming back I had an idea for a small project, a &amp;ldquo;guess who&amp;rdquo; app that I vibecoded in a few hours with &lt;a href=&#34;https://firebase.studio/&#34;&gt;Firebase Studio&lt;/a&gt;. It got me a Next.js+tailwindcss app pretty quickly, with LLM calls handled by &lt;a href=&#34;https://genkit.dev/&#34;&gt;Genkit&lt;/a&gt;. Originally it was using the Gemini API and hosted on Firebase, but I&amp;rsquo;ve changed it to GPT-5 and Fly.io for hosting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training a small LLM</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-08-16-training-a-small-llm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-08-16-training-a-small-llm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So in my [last post about Pilish]({% post_url 2025-08-09-pillmish %}) I mentioned that a follow up to get better results would be to use a LLM with word level tokenization. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a bad idea in general because the vocabulary size can be huge, and that&amp;rsquo;s why most LLM these days use BPE or subword tokenization, but I decided to give it a quick try and train a LLM from scratch with word level tokenization. Back in 2023 I used to be quite into finetuning and all that but this year I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much low level tinkering with LLM so it was a good exercise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pillmish</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-08-09-pillmish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-08-09-pillmish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I heard about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pilish&#34;&gt;Pilish&lt;/a&gt; for the first time. As Wikipedia puts it, &lt;code&gt;Pilish is a style of constrained writing in which the lengths of consecutive words or sentences match the digits of the number π (pi).&lt;/code&gt; My second thought (right after &amp;ldquo;who would enjoy doing that&amp;rdquo;) was, this sounds easy for LLMs! So I set out to make a minimal proof of concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long story short, the trick is to constrain the output to follow the digits of Pi—the same way that structured output (JSON, etc.) works. With Hugging Face Transformers, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to do with a custom &lt;code&gt;logits_processor&lt;/code&gt;. Here, we just constrain the tokens to those matching the desired number of characters at each step. I shared the code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/MarhicJeromeGIT/d01f79363420c8c10d5aeba10c4c9960&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>August 2025 Update (GPT-5, Veo 3, Gemini CLI, Open Source)</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-08-08-august-2025-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-08-08-august-2025-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lot of things going on this summer, but yesterday&amp;rsquo;s big news was the release of ChatGPT 5. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an opinion on it yet, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a single model (at least exposed, even if this is routed under the hood) instead of switching between 4o and o4-mini-high, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the market for a &amp;ldquo;CLI Agent&amp;rdquo; (synchronous, like Claude Code, not async like Devin and co.). I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli&#34;&gt;Gemini CLI&lt;/a&gt; with good results — as long as I&amp;rsquo;m within the free PRO requests. As soon as it switches to the &amp;ldquo;flash&amp;rdquo; model it becomes useless, can&amp;rsquo;t edit a file properly, and just loops on itself. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t pay for it. Claude Code seems too expensive; I might give &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openai/codex&#34;&gt;OpenAI Codex&lt;/a&gt; a try with GPT-5, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard much about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maths notes (1)</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-07-30-maths-notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-07-30-maths-notes-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I started reading a paper about diffusion (the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2006.11239&#34;&gt;DDPM paper&lt;/a&gt;) and I was quickly out of my depth. I needed a refresher about probabilities, and actually even more basic stuff like exponential and integration. And I thought why not share the notes here! So this blog post is the content of a python notebook about exponential and the normal distribution, exported to markdown with &lt;code&gt;jupyter nbconvert&lt;/code&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not deep or anything, just a nice refresher for myself. Kind of a pain to write math formulas and get them displayed in my Jekyll blog but got it working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mathjax.org/&#34;&gt;Mathjax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I apologize for the confusion. You&#39;re absolutely right.</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-07-25-i-apologize-for-the-confusion-you-re-absolutely-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-07-25-i-apologize-for-the-confusion-you-re-absolutely-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google did me dirty this week and I&amp;rsquo;m salty, so let me tell you. The other day I received an email informing me that my YouTube Premium subscription had been renewed, which surprised me because I canceled it about 6 months ago, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed it ever since (thanks, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp&#34;&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt;!). I first thought it was my daughter&amp;rsquo;s shenanigans, but after a closer look I had only &amp;ldquo;paused&amp;rdquo; the subscription instead of canceling it, and Google conveniently failed to inform me it was going to be restarted&amp;hellip; No advance email like &amp;ldquo;your subscription will restart in a few days,&amp;rdquo; just &amp;ldquo;whoops, we restarted your subscription and you&amp;rsquo;ve been charged 13 euros, teehee.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>July Update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-07-05-july-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-07-05-july-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick update to say I am still making progress on the Password Game Agent project I mentioned last post. I have now reached up to step 16 where we need to solve a chess position&amp;hellip; Seems like a suitable job for a reasoning model !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Step 16 of the password game require solving a chess puzzle.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.jmarhic.com/assets/images/password_game_step16.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main changes that enabled going from step 11 (Wordle answer) to 16 were adding a &amp;ldquo;search tool&amp;rdquo; based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/docs/guides/tools-web-search&#34;&gt;OpenAI web search tool&lt;/a&gt; and changing the reasoning effort from &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;high&amp;rdquo;.
The current version of the code is here : &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goverture/password-game-agent/blob/master/manually.py&#34;&gt;https://github.com/goverture/password-game-agent/blob/master/manually.py&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m still making regular changes and trying new ideas to make progress. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed we often seem to get stuck for various reason (for instance a badly recognized Capcha), so I want to add a new step to ensure that we make progress consistently, or backtrack, in order to not get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The password game agent</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-06-18-the-password-game-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-06-18-the-password-game-agent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is this javascript game called &lt;a href=&#34;https://neal.fun/password-game/&#34;&gt;The Password Game&lt;/a&gt; where you have to chose a password, following increasingly ludicrous requirements.
Agentic coding/research is all the rage today and I got the idea of making an &amp;ldquo;agent&amp;rdquo; that would solve it. Conceptually it&amp;rsquo;s just about calling a LLM in a loop, giving it the proper tools and context until it solved the task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where I got so far, using ChatGPT 4o and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/playwright-mcp&#34;&gt;Playwright MCP&lt;/a&gt; (only gave it the navigate and type tools for now). It&amp;rsquo;s solving correctly the first few steps, but gets stuck at the &amp;ldquo;sponsor&amp;rdquo; rule because it cannot view the image. The next step is to give it access to the playwright&amp;rsquo;s screenshot tool. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how far it can go !&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-05-25-may-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-05-25-may-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another May update ! Not much going on as usual, rainy season arrived in Ho Chi Minh city so we get some strong rain and nice sunsets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Rainy season sunset&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.jmarhic.com/assets/images/sunset.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we got the announcement that &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/future-of-pocket&#34;&gt;Pocket was saying goodbye&lt;/a&gt;. Kind of bummed because I found the service convenient, though I just used it as a link bookmark (I never cared much about the reading mode, I always go to the original link - though apparently that worked well with the Kobo e-reader). Anyway I switched to a self-hosted alternative immediately: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallabag.org/&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of sluggish but it does the job, and it has an Android app so I can still &amp;ldquo;share link&amp;rdquo; to save a link from my phone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First MCP server</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-05-04-my-first-mcp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-05-04-my-first-mcp-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So MCP is all the rage these days, and it&amp;rsquo;s not very complex: it&amp;rsquo;s basically a standardized way to provide tools to LLMs. So you have an RPC server that provides a description of the tools and the parameters they expect, and your client (a LLM based application) can connect to it and tell the LLM what tools are available, and the LLM can decide to call them when appropriate. Easy stuff and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/modelcontextprotocol/typescript-sdk&#34;&gt;SDK provided&lt;/a&gt; do most of the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-04-12-april-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-04-12-april-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly with a newborn and a very sticky 3 years old at home, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been doing much in the past 3 weeks. Since I stopped working on it, I&amp;rsquo;ve released my thematic crossword generation app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://prosettr.com&#34;&gt;Prosettr&lt;/a&gt;, to a complete (and expected) indifference (zero traffic came from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=43521279&#34;&gt;HackerNews announcement&lt;/a&gt;, and I got about 10 likes from LinkedIn). Oh well, it was a fun project anyway and I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the result!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Liam</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-03-23-welcome-to-liam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-03-23-welcome-to-liam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My son Liam was born this Monday! He is healthy and everything is good. I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched the computer for the week, and as a result I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything technical to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week before however I gave a try to &lt;a href=&#34;https://browser-use.com/&#34;&gt;Browser Use&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that allows LLMs to use the browser more effectively. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read in detail how it works but it seems to highlight the interactive areas (buttons etc.) and then take a screenshot for analysis, instead of only sending the DOM as text. It worked pretty well, I was able to fill a form entirely with it (prompting it to not press submit!), and to use Google Translate as well. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a special use case idea for it at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First steps with CDK</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-03-09-trying-cdk-and-k6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-03-09-trying-cdk-and-k6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not much going on these days. At work, we started migrating some apps from Google App Engine to AWS, which gave me a chance to learn about &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cdk/v2/guide/home.html&#34;&gt;AWS CDK&lt;/a&gt;. As a learning step, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a small template to deploy a static website on S3 + CloudFront for the frontend and ALB + ECS for the backend, with some CloudFront behaviors, Route 53, and ACM certificates sprinkled in. As far as I know, it&amp;rsquo;s a standard architecture (though I need to lock down the S3 permissions a bit more, add logs to CloudWatch, etc.), and it&amp;rsquo;s really nice that it is reviewable by our security guy before we deploy it. And also, it can be deployed to staging first and later on to production with little to no changes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-28-february-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-28-february-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February went by in a blink! I barely had any time for myself this month between work, a pregnant wife, and my 2-year-old being in the &amp;ldquo;I want papa only&amp;rdquo; phase. These days, the first thing I do in the morning is play Lego. It beats doomscrolling, but at 7 a.m. and before my coffee, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to be creative. Here&amp;rsquo;s an elephant I made this morning—the trunk moves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jmarhic.com/assets/images/lego_elephant.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An elephant in Lego&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also rewritten a big part of the backend of &lt;a href=&#34;https://prosettr.com&#34;&gt;Prosettr.com&lt;/a&gt;. In a HackerNews thread about Donald Knuth (&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42970240&#34;&gt;Donald Knuth&amp;rsquo;s 2024 Christmas Lecture: Strong and Weak Components&lt;/a&gt;), I learned there was an improvement to the algorithm that my app is based on, Dancing Links. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into much detail here (maybe in a future post), but I procured &lt;em&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/em&gt; Volume 4B, and indeed, the improved version uses half the memory, with each option&amp;rsquo;s items having only up and down links, and no left and right links—those being replaced by a &amp;ldquo;spacer&amp;rdquo; node. Here&amp;rsquo;s my original implementation in Go I made while following the chapter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goverture/exact_cover/blob/master/examples/backtrack_aocp/main.go&#34;&gt;/backtrack_aocp/main.go&lt;/a&gt;. Then I replaced the previous implementation with this one, with some added optimizations (support for secondary columns, using channels instead of an input matrix, another channel to output the solutions, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fed up with Google ads</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-14-google-ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-14-google-ads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I just got a Galaxy S 23 FE phone to replace my recently lost Realme crapphone. And&amp;hellip; frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s not much better. It came loaded with a LOT of bloat: Samsung apps (Galaxy Shop?), Microsoft apps (Copilot, Linkedin&amp;hellip;), Netflix, and a bunch of crapware like &amp;ldquo;AR Doodle&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;AR Emoji&amp;rdquo; that are somehow running in the background. Of course, I cannot uninstall any of those without rooting my phone, if it&amp;rsquo;s even possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January 2025 retrospective</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-03-january-2025-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-03-january-2025-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pretty good start to the year overall, I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to keep writing blog posts regularly. Not sure if anyone is reading them as there is no comment system and I don&amp;rsquo;t have any analytics set up yet, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter for now—I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to get better at writing first. Mostly, I&amp;rsquo;m writing them as a memento, something I can look back on in the future, and also for the chance of influencing future LLMs, if only a tiny bit, with some of myself. I enjoyed a blog post about it recently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2025/01/25/AI-Slop-Suspicion-and-Writing-Back&#34;&gt;AI Slop, Suspicion, and Writing Back by Ben Congdon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI o3-mini first impressions</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-02-openai-o3-mini-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-02-02-openai-o3-mini-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, OpenAI released their latest model, &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/index/openai-o3-mini/&#34;&gt;OpenAI o3-mini&lt;/a&gt;, a follow-up to the reasoning models o1 and o1-mini. They were immediately available on chatgpt.com, so I had a chance to put them to work. I had a simple task in mind (writing a Python script that would prompt an LLM to rate a list of words for use in my crossword app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://prosettr.com&#34;&gt;prosettr.com&lt;/a&gt;). The first output was good, but when I asked for a few minor tweaks I was presented with a refusal:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Lunar New Year</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-27-happy-lunar-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-27-happy-lunar-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week it&amp;rsquo;s Lunar New Year, or Têt celebrations in Vietnam. Which means my daughter&amp;rsquo;s school is off, which means I get approximately 30 seconds of free time per day. Despite that, it was hard to miss the hype regarding the release of Deepseek R1. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to read the paper or anything, but I gave it a quick try at &lt;a href=&#34;chat.deepseek.com&#34;&gt;chat.deepseek.com&lt;/a&gt;. I still don&amp;rsquo;t have a good handle on what is a good &amp;ldquo;reasoning question,&amp;rdquo; but I came up with a good use case today: coming up with a memorable port number for a service I&amp;rsquo;m hosting locally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP my Pixel 4a</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-22-rip-my-pixel-4a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-22-rip-my-pixel-4a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 7th of January, I received this surprising email from Google:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Jerome,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to let you know about an upcoming software update for your Pixel 4a that will affect the overall performance and stability of its battery. Pixel phones, like other smartphones, use rechargeable lithium-ion batteries that, over time, may experience performance, capacity, or runtime degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, your Pixel 4a will receive an automatic software update to Android 13 that introduces new battery management features to improve the stability of the battery. This update will reduce your battery’s runtime and charging performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January 2025, Second Week Update</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-14-january-2025-second-week-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-14-january-2025-second-week-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Already two weeks into January, it&amp;rsquo;s time for an update on my projects! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with the progress on &lt;a href=&#34;https://prosettr.com&#34;&gt;Prosettr.com&lt;/a&gt;, my crossword generation app. It will soon be time to share it with the world (HackerNews&amp;hellip;). Yesterday evening, I added login functionality (a choice of email + password or Google sign-in) using Firebase Authentication, as well as a button to load PUZ files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter was surprisingly easy to do: I gave ChatGPT o1-mini the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sliminality/dab21fa834eae0a70193c7cd69c356d5&#34;&gt;PUZ format description&lt;/a&gt; and asked it for a loader/writer in Go with my expectations for the input/output, followed by an HTTP handler. Thirty minutes later, here we are with the &amp;ldquo;Upload PUZ File&amp;rdquo; in production!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First week of 2025</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-06-first-week-of-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-06-first-week-of-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;2025-is-off-to-a-pretty-good-start&#34;&gt;2025 is off to a pretty good start!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent 3 days alone in Phu Quoc to recharge, didn’t do anything except swimming and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60018639-thistlefoot&#34;&gt;reading Thistlefoot&lt;/a&gt; while drinking coconuts. I used to go regularly when I was single, but now it&amp;rsquo;s going to be my last trip for a while. Got lucky with the weather as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Phu Quoc picture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://blog.jmarhic.com/assets/images/onglang_beach_phu_quoc_2024.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back home, I’ve made some progress on my crossword solver app. I opened a WebSocket to stream the intermediary results (&amp;ldquo;dead ends&amp;rdquo;) as the backtracking algorithm progresses; I think it looks cool. In the frontend, I’ve added a history so you can Ctrl-Z, and other minor convenience changes (right-click to toggle between black and white cells, etc). I should define the scope, though; I don’t plan to make it a full-blown &amp;ldquo;crossword editor.&amp;rdquo; I think I will just add the ability to export a grid and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And a Happy New Year! (2025)</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-02-and-a-happy-new-year-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2025-01-02-and-a-happy-new-year-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking back, 2024 was a pretty good year across all metrics! Learned new things at work even though it&amp;rsquo;s my 5th year at the job, been pretty healthy and fit, not been drinking much (was a dry NYE, and will be doing a dry January). So I&amp;rsquo;m not taking any big resolutions for this year; it should be plenty busy already with the birth of my second kid in a few months. I&amp;rsquo;ll just try to finish and release my crossword generator application before that, and that will be it. Maybe try to be more smiley and relaxed in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I use GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2024-12-25-how-i-use-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2024-12-25-how-i-use-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the release of ChatGPT more than 2 years ago, I have felt a strong disconnect with the opinions on HackerNews about AI. It really feels like an Anti-AI (especially anti-OpenAI) echo chamber, neverendingly predicting the advent of AI winters, always repeating the same arguments (usually some flavor of &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not intelligent&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;what is AGI?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;how can you trust it?&amp;rdquo;). Well, given that the generated code compiles, the tests pass and the program works as expected, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what there is to complain about. I feel that HN is about as wrong about AI as it was about cryptocurrencies. Eventually, I mostly stopped reading the comments, I just use it as a link aggregator now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2024-12-25-merry-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2024-12-25-merry-christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a day off on this Christmas day, and I got inspired to revive this blog by reading Simon Willison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;approach to running a link blog&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I like his blog to keep updated about the new models&amp;rsquo; capabilities and developments in the AI world in general. He makes small experiments to put the models into practice, with a good dose of enthusiasm, and I want to follow a similar approach for this blog: sharing interesting articles I read, and some of my daily programming experiments, while &lt;a href=&#34;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/#trying-to-add-something-extra&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;trying to add something extra&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rate Limit</title>
      <link>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2024-10-26-rate-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.jmarhic.com/post/2024-10-26-rate-limit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss various common ways of handling API rate limits, and I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce a new tool I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goverture/meter_flow&#34;&gt;MeterFlow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most APIs have rate limits, usually counted in requests per minute, but other resources can be limited as well (for instance, the number of characters you can translate with the Google Translate API, or the number of tokens you can generate with some LLM API). When you exceed the rate limit, the API will return a 429 status code, telling you to slow down. There are various ways of dealing with API rate limits in your code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
